# 大家好 現在白天太熱啦
Hi everyone. It's too hot in the day recently.
# 所以晚上出來活動
So we're coming out at night.
# 來夾點魚 看下有沒有黃鱔啊 看下有沒有蛇頭魚
We're gonna catch some fish. Let's see if there are any eels, see if there are any snakehead fish.
# 我家附近的魚全部都夾完啦 小魚都看不到
I've caught all the fish around my place. I can't even see any small fish there.
# 看下攝影小哥家附近有沒有
Let's see if there are any around Mr. Cameraman's home.
# 這裡有條小溝哦
Here's a small pit.
# 應該有魚
There should be fish.
# 哇 這裡有小魚呦
Wa! Here are some small fish.
# 那麼小的 放過它吧
Leave them alone. They're so small.
# 我等它長大了我再來
I'll come again when they grow up.
# 這條水泥溝的話應該沒有多少大魚
I don't think there are a lot of fish in this pit.
# 我去下面看一下
Let me go down there and have a look.
# 你看 那裡好多小蝌蚪
Look! There are a lot of tadpoles.
# 剛出生沒多久的
They just came out from the eggs not long ago.
# 你看 這裡有一個
Look! Here's a...
# 你看 這種青蛙 好瘦啊它
Look! This kind of frog...It's so skinny.
# 肯定找不到東西吃
It must have difficulties in finding food.
# 它這種青蛙是 吃那個 小蟲子的哦
This kind of frogs, they feed on, on little bugs, you know.
# 這個是莊稼的守護
They are the frogs that corps, corps
# 守護莊稼的那個青蛙
that guard the crops.
# 不能 不能把它抓啦
No one, no one should catch them.
# 我把它放生
I'm gonna release it.
# 跑
Run!
# 兄弟家的梨樹 梨古
This is my buddy's pear tree, pear.
# 現在越來越大了哦
Now it's getting larger and larger.
# 就看到一個 白天還看見很多
I see just one. I can see a lot in the day.
# 這大晚上的看不到
But I can't see any at night.
# 應該都躲起來啊
They must be hiding away.
# 等熟了時候再來
I'll come again when they're ripe.
# 你看 這是螢火蟲哦
Look! This is a firefly.
# 它屁股後面都是發亮的
It glows at the back of the butt.
# 你信你把燈關掉看一下
Switch off the light and you'll see, if you don't trust me.
# 是不是
Am I right?
# 一亮一亮的
Twinkle twinkle
# 喂 開始飛啦 它馬上想飛走啦
Hey, it starts flying. It wants to fly away now.
# 愛護蟲子 人人有責哦
Protecting bugs is the responsibility of everyone.
# 飛吧 不知道飛哪裡去啦
Fly! Who knows where it is now.
# 找都找不到啦
I can't find it anymore.
# 你自由啦
You're free now.
# 幸好是碰到我
You should feel blessed that it's me.
# 你看這個 我還以為是個雞蛋呢
Have a look at this one. I thought that it were an egg.
# 原來是個毒蘑菇
But it's a poisonous mushroom.
# 像一條蛇一樣的
It's like a snake.
# 這樣的招澤地很多黃鱔跟泥鰍的哦
There are always a lot of eels and loaches in this kind of ponds.
# 有點嚇人啊這裡
It's a bit scary here.
# 你看 這裡有一條 小泥 小黃鱔
Look! Here's a small loa.. a small eel.
# 差點跑啦
It's almost gone.
# 這裡還有沒有
Any more here?
# 要很小心 走這樣的路
Special cares need to be taken, while walking on this kind of surface.
# 你看 這裡還有一條
Look! Here's another one.
# 這裡有一條
Here's one.
# 那麼大的
It's so big.
# 幸好我帶了桶
Fortunately, I have a bucket with me.
# 這裡有一條
Here's one.
# 跑啦 這泥鰍
It runs away, this loach.
# 跑啦
Run away...
# 這裡沒有了
No more here
# 溝裡面 去溝裡面看下有沒有
Into the pit, let's go into the pit and see if there are any.
# 這有個蛇頭魚呦
Here's a snakehead fish.
# 誒呦 抓到啦
Eyo! I got it!
# 看見沒有 你看
See? Look!
# 一條那麼小的蛇頭魚
It's a tiny snakehead fish.
# 被我逮到啦
And I've caught it.
# 想跑
You wanna run away?
# 你看這個魚
Have a look at this fish!
# 那麼兇
It's so fierce.
# 哇 你看 這裡有條蛇頭魚
Wa! Look! Here's a snakehead fish.
# 看見沒有 我看到它尾巴
See? I can see its tail,
# 也看到它頭
and also its head.
# 哪裡去了
Where is it now?
# 在草裡面
It's in the grass.
# 誒 沒撈到 撈到泥巴
Eh? I couldn't catch it? It's only mud here.
# 不在了
It's not here.
# 剛剛還看到它在這裡的
I just saw it here a couple of seconds ago.
# 誒呦 那麼難搞 這蛇頭魚就是這樣
Eyo! It's so hard. Well, this is snakehead fish.
# 一鑽到泥上去就
Once they squeeze into the mud,
# 怎麼找都找不到啦
you can never find it.
# 你看 這裡有一條 看到沒有 剛好動了一下
Look! Here's one. See? It just shook a little bit.
# 把水都搞渾濁啦
The water is so muddy now.
# 你看 這有一條蛇頭魚
Look! Here's a snakehead fish.
# 啊 它鑽泥
Ah! It squeezes into the mud.
# 鑽泥也跑不掉 你看抓到啦
Squeeze into the mud or not, it's not gonna run away. Look! I got it now.
# 你看 這裡有條小的蛇頭魚 看到沒有 太小啦
Look! Here's a small snakehead fish. See? It's too small.
# 抓到啦 那麼小
Got it! It's so small.
# 那麼小也不放過
But size doesn't matter.
# 你看 這條泥鰍
Look! This loach...
# 看能不能夾住它
Let's see if I can catch it.
# 別跑
Freeze!
# 跑啦
Run away...
# 嘿 想跑 這樣都被我抓住
Hey! Wanna run away? I can still catch you.
# 你看 抓了一晚上就抓了那麼一點點
Look! We've spent the whole night, only to have just a tiny little bit here.
# 蛇頭魚跟黃鱔
Snakehead fish, and eels
# 泥鰍就搞了幾條
and some loaches
# 現在都快十二點啦
It's almost midnight now.
# 就抓了那麼一點點 (註︰沒有原字幕)
And we have just a tiny little bit here.
# 要準備回去啦 不回去的話 要駡人啦
We gotta get ready to go home. Somebody's gonna get mad otherwise.